ucd.ie 2018-12-10

# University College Dublin - Privacy

## Ráiteas Príobháideachta

### Introduction

University College Dublin has published this Privacy Statement to demonstrate our firm commitment to the privacy of users of our Website. It applies to the use of your personal information (also known as ‘personal data’) by University College Dublin through the viewing oruse of its main website ([www.ucd.ie](https://www.ucd.ie/)) or any website within the University College Dublin domainwhich has pointed you to this page. The information published here is limited to the use ofpersonal information by University websites hosted under the ucd.ie domain only. The Universitydoes not accept responsibility for the content or privacy practices of other external websites.External links to other websites are not always clearly identifiable as such. Within the UCD domain you may find websites over which the University does not maintain editorial responsibility or direct control. Such sites can include the websites of student organisations etc. While UCD encourages compliance with this web privacy statement at such sites, please consult the privacy statements of individual sites or contact the persons responsible for those sites, in order to understand the policies and practices under which they operate.

**General statement**

University College Dublin fully respects your right to privacy and actively seeks to preserve the privacy rights of those who share information with the University. Any personal information you provide to the University will be treated with the highest standards of security and confidentiality, in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) as introduced in May 2018.

**Processing of personal information**

University College Dublin does not collect any personal data about you on this website apart from information you volunteer, for example by emailing the University. Any information you provide is not made available to any third parties, other than those working with the University on normal University business and is used by the University only in accordance with the purpose for which you provided the information and will only be retained for as long as required for the purpose.

The University will not process any personal information about you on this website without your permission, save in cases where the University is required by law to do so, such as the investigation of a criminal offence by the Gardai, or a breach of the UCD Information Technology Services Acceptable Use Policy.

This is normally stated on the web-page where the information is requested and should be self-explanatory. However, if you have any specific queries about the purpose for which your information is to be used, you should contact our Information Compliance Manager before submitting the information. University policy and procedures relating to the processing of personal data, including your rights of rectification and your responsibilities as providers of personal information, are available at http://www.ucd.ie/dataprotection

**Processing of technical information**

Cookies may be used by the University websites to collect non-personal information about how visitors use our websites or to remember display preferences. Temporary session cookies may also be used on some websites to enable specific functionality (e.g. UCD Connect portal) and no information is retained once the “session” is complete.

Occasionally cookie information is passed to third parties for analysing website activity and usage. This information will not include any of your personal information from which you will be readily identifiable. Further Information regarding UCD’ cookie usage is available at <http://www.ucd.ie/cookie-policy/>

Technical details in connection with visits to this website may be logged on the University’s server for accounting and auditing purposes (e.g. Computer IP number). It is the policy of the University not to disclose such technical information in respect of individual website visitors to any third party unless obliged to disclose such information by a rule of law. The technical information will be used only for statistical and other administrative purposes. You should note that technical details, which the University cannot associate with any identifiable individual, do not constitute "personal data" for the purposes of the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003 and General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) 2018.

**Access and Rectification**

If you become aware of any inaccuracy in the personal data you have supplied to us, please let us know and we will update our records accordingly. Under General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) you have a right to have incorrect or incomplete data corrected or erased by the University. You can do this by contacting us at any of the contact points listed below.

Pursuant to General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) you have certain rights to obtain a copy of the data held by you. For assistance in exercising these rights, please refer to the university data protection webpages as set out below.

**Security**

We take appropriate physical and technical security measures, including staff awareness training to maintain the security of personal data supplied to us and we review these measures regularly.

**Review**

This Privacy Statement explains the privacy policy that the University has adopted for its websites. However, in legal terms it shall not be construed as a contractual undertaking. The University reserves the right to review and amend this Statement at any time without notice and you should check this page regularly to view the most up to date Privacy Statement.

**Further Information and Contact Details**

Further information on your data privacy rights is available on the website of the Data Protection

If you have any questions relating to the processing of personal data on this Website please contact the Information Compliance Manager at the address set out below.

Information Compliance Manager

UCD Records Management and Freedom of Information Unit

Roebuck Castle

University College Dublin

Belfield

Dublin 4

Telephone: +353 1 716 8786/8722
